{
    "translations": {
      "en": {
        "q4": {
          "type": "select",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.",
          "question":"Which strings can be matched with the regular expression $a+ab$",
          "answer": ["a",
            "ab"
          ],
          "choices": ["a", "aba", "ab", "baa"]
        },
        "q5": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.<br />'.': The Concatenation operator. This operator is used to concate strings together.",
          "question":"Which strings can be matched with the regular expression $a \\cdot ab$",
          "answer": ["aab"
          ],
          "choices": ["a", "ab", "aab", "baa"]
        },
        "q6": {
          "type": "select",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.<br />'.': The Concatenation operator. This operator is used to concate strings together. We often omit showing the '⋅' for concatenation.",
          "question":"Suppose we have 2 regular expressions: $x = a$, and $y = ab$. Which of the following equals $xy$",
          "answer": ["$x\\cdot y$",
            "a.ab",
            "aab"
          ],
          "choices": ["$x\\cdot y$", "a.ab", "aab"]
        },
        "q7": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.<br />'.': The Concatenation operator. This operator is used to concate strings together.<br />'*': Strar-Closure. This operator means to repeat for Zero or More times.",
          "question":"Suppose we have RegEx $r = a$, which of the following is the Language represented by $r$, $L(r^*)$?",
          "answer": ["$\\{a^n\\mid n\\ge0\\}$"],
          "choices": ["$\\lambda$","a", "aa", "aaa","aaaaaaaaa", "$\\{a^n\\mid n\\ge0\\}$"]
        },
        "q8": {
          "type": "select",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.<br />'.': The Concatenation operator. This operator is used to concate strings together.<br />'*': Strar-Closure. This operator means to repeat for Zero or More times.",
          "question":"Suppose we have RegEx $r = a$, which of the following stings belong to $L(r^*)$?",
          "answer": ["$\\lambda$","a", "aa", "aaa","aaaaaaaaa"],
          "choices": ["$\\lambda$","a", "aa", "aaa","aaaaaaaaa", "aaaab"]
        },
        "q9": {
          "type": "select",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.<br />'.': The Concatenation operator. This operator is used to concate strings together.<br />'*': Strar-Closure. This operator means to repeat for Zero or More times.",
          "question":"Suppose we have RegEx $r = a$, and $s = b$, which of the following is $L((r+s)^*)$?",
          "answer": ["$\\{w\\mid w\\in \\{a, b\\}^*\\}$", "any string from $a$s and $b$s"],
          "choices": ["ab", "aba", "baaa","aababababa", "$\\{w\\mid w\\in \\{a, b\\}^*\\}$", "any string from $a$s and $b$s"]
        },
        "q10": {
          "type": "select",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.<br />'.': The Concatenation operator. This operator is used to concate strings together.<br />'*': Strar-Closure. This operator means to repeat for Zero or More times.",
          "question":"Suppose we have RegEx $r = a$, and $s = b$, which of the following is the result of the expression $(r+b)^*$?",
          "answer": ["ab", "aba", "baaa","aababababa"],
          "choices": ["ab", "aba", "baaa","aababababa"]
        },
        "q11": {
          "type": "select",
          "description": "$\\textbf{Basic Operators:}$<br />'+': The union operator. This operator is equivalent to the Bolloean 'OR' operator.<br />'.': The Concatenation operator. This operator is used to concate strings together.<br />'*': Strar-Closure. This operator means to repeat for Zero or More times.",
          "question":"Suppose we have RegEx $r = aa$, which of the following is equivalent to the expression $r^*$?",
          "answer": ["$(aa)^*$","$\\{w \\mid$ w is even number of $a$s$, w\\in \\{a\\}^*\\}$", "any string with even $a$s, where $\\Sigma = \\{a\\}$"],
          "choices": ["$aa^*$", "$(aa)^*$", "$\\{w \\mid$ w is even number of a's$, w\\in \\{a,b\\}^*\\}$","$\\{w \\mid$ w is even number of $a$s$, w\\in \\{a\\}^*\\}$", "any string with even $a$s, where $\\Sigma = \\{a\\}$"]
        },
        "q12": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What language can the following equation be? $(a+b)^∗ \\cdot a \\cdot (a+b)^∗$ = $(a+b)^∗a(a+b)^∗$",
          "description": "There are three operators that can be used:<br> $+$ union (OR),<br> $\\cdot$ concatenation (AND),<br> $\\ast$ star-closure (repeat 0 or more times).<br> We often omit showing the $\\cdot$ for concatenation.",
          "answer": "All strings from $\\{a,b\\}^∗$ that contain at least one $a$",
          "choices": ["All strings from $\\{a,b\\}^∗$", "All strings from $\\{a,b\\}^∗$ that contain at least one $a$"]
        },

        "q13": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"Suppose $\\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}$, which of the following are valid regular expressions?",
          "description": "Definition: Given $\\Sigma$<br>$\\textbf {1.}$ $\\emptyset$, $\\lambda$, and $a$ $\\in$ $\\Sigma$ are R.E.",
          "answer": ["$\\emptyset$", "$\\lambda$", "$a$", "$b$", "$c$"],
          "choices": ["$\\emptyset$", "$\\lambda$", "$a$", "$b$", "$c$"]
        },
        "q14": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"Suppose $\\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}$, which of the following are valid regular expressions?",
          "description": "Definition: Given $\\Sigma$<br>$\\textbf {1.}$ $\\emptyset$, $\\lambda$, and $a$ $\\in$ $\\Sigma$ are R.E.<br> $\\textbf {2.}$ If r and s are regular expressions, then $r$ $+$ $s$, $rs$, $r^∗$ are R.E.",
          "answer": ["$a+\\lambda$", "$a + b$", "$b+c$", "$a+b+c$", "$abc$", "$ac$", "$(a)$", "$b^*$"],
          "choices": ["$a+\\lambda$", "$a + b$", "$b+c$", "$a+b+c$", "$abc$", "$ac$", "$(a)$", "$b^*$"]
        },
        "q15": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"Suppose $\\Sigma = \\{a, b, c\\}$, which of the following are valid regular expressions?",
          "description": "Definition: Given $\\Sigma$<br>$\\textbf {1.}$ $\\emptyset$, $\\lambda$, and $a$ $\\in$ $\\Sigma$ are R.E.<br> $\\textbf {2.}$ If r and s are regular expressions, then $r$ $+$ $s$, $rs$, $r^∗$ are R.E.<br> $\\textbf {3.}$ r is a R.E if and only if it can be derived from (1) with a finite number of applications of (2)",
          "answer": ["$(\\lambda + a)^*bb(c)$", "$ab^*c$", "$b(ba)c^*$"],
          "choices": ["$(\\lambda + a)^*bb(c)$", "$ab^*c$", "$b(ba)c^*$"]
        },
        "q16": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"Select all true statements",
          "description": "Definition: $L(r)$ is the language denoted by regular expression $r$. <br> $\\textbf{1.}$ $\\emptyset$, {$\\lambda$}, and $\\{a\\in \\Sigma\\}$ are each languages denoted by some R.E.",
          "answer": ["$\\emptyset = \\{\\}$", "$L(\\lambda) = \\{\\lambda\\}$", "$\\lambda$ is empty string", "$\\emptyset$ means no strings at all"],
          "choices": ["$\\emptyset = \\{\\}$", "$L(\\lambda) = \\{\\lambda\\}$", "$L(\\lambda) = \\{\\}$", "$\\emptyset = \\lambda$", "$\\lambda$ is empty string", "$\\emptyset$ means no strings at all"]
        },
        "q17": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"Which of the following equals $L(a+b+c^*)$",
          "description": "Definition: $L(r)$ is the language denoted by regular expression $r$. <br> $\\textbf{1.}$ $\\emptyset$, {$\\lambda$}, and $\\{a\\in \\Sigma\\}$ are each languages denoted by some R.E. <br> Note that $\\emptyset$ $=$ $\\{\\}$ (the empty set), while $\\lambda$ $=$ $\\{\\lambda\\}$, meaning the set containing just the empty string.",
          "answer": ["$L(a+b)\\cup L(c^*)$", "$L(a)\\cup L(b)\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a\\}\\cup L(b)\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a\\}\\cup\\{b\\}\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a,b\\}\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a,b\\}\\cup\\{\\lambda, c, cc, ccc, ...)$", "$\\{\\lambda, a, b, c, cc, ccc, ...)$"],
          "choices": ["$L(a+b)\\cup L(c^*)$", "$L(a)\\cup L(b)\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a\\}\\cup L(b)\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a\\}\\cup\\{b\\}\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a,b\\}\\cup L(c^*)$", "$\\{a,b\\}\\cup\\{\\lambda, c, cc, ccc, ...)$", "$\\{\\lambda, a, b, c, cc, ccc, ...)$"]
        },
        "q18": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What can be a substitute of $a(b^∗)+c$",
          "description": "Precedence Rule: <br> $∗$ : highest <br> $\\cdot$  <br> $+$ : lowest",
          "answer": "$(a(b)^∗)+c$",
          "choices": ["$(ab)^*+c$", "$a^*b+c$","$(a(b)^∗)+c$", "$ab^*+c$"]
        },
        "q19": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"What is the RegEx for $L = \\{w \\in {\\Sigma}^{*} \\mid w$ has an odd number of $a$‘s followed by an even number of $b$‘s}, where $\\Sigma = \\{a,b\\}$" ,
          "description": "Examples",
          "answer": ["$(aa)^*a(bb)^*$", "$a(aa)^*(bb)^*$"],
          "choices": ["$(aa)^*a(bb)^*$", "$a(aa)^*(bb)^*$", "$aaa^*bb^*$", "$(aaa)^*(bb)^*$", "$(aaa)^*bb^*$"]
        },
        "q20": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"Does for $L = \\{w \\in {\\Sigma}^{*} \\mid w$ has an odd number of $a$‘s followed by an even number of $b$‘s} has the empty string" ,
          "description": "Examples",
          "answer": "No",
          "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
        },
        "q21": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"What is the RegEx $L = \\{w \\in {\\Sigma}^{*} \\mid w$ has no more than three $a$s and must end in $ab$}, where $\\Sigma = \\{a,b\\}$?",
          "description": "Examples",
          "answer": ["$b^{*}(ab^{*} + ab^{*}ab^{*} + \\lambda)ab$", "$(b^{*}ab^{*} + b^{*}ab^{*}ab^{*} + b^{*})ab$", "$b^{*}ab^{*}ab + b^{*}ab^{*}ab^{*}ab + b^{*}ab$"],
          "choices": ["$(a+aa+\\lambda)ab$","$(a+aa+aaa+\\lambda)ab$","$b^{*}(ab^{*} + ab^{*}ab^{*} + \\lambda)ab$", "$b^{*}(ab^{*} + ab^{*}ab^{*}+ ab^{*}ab^{*}ab^{*} + \\lambda)ab$", "$(b^{*}ab^{*} + b^{*}ab^{*}ab^{*} + b^{*})ab$", "$b^{*}ab^{*}ab + b^{*}ab^{*}ab^{*}ab + b^{*}ab$"]
        },
        "q22": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What is the Language for $0 + (- + \\lambda)((1+2+\\ldots +9)(0+1+2+\\ldots +9)^{*})$?",
          "description": "Examples",
          "answer": "Positive and Negative numbers",
          "choices": ["Positive and Negative numbers", "Positive numbers", "Negative numbers"]
        },
        "q23": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"Can every finite set of strings be described by a R.E.?",
          "description": "Examples",
          "answer": "Yes",
          "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
        },

        "q60": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What is the transition from state $\\{q4\\}$ with the alphabet a?",
          "description": "Transition state nodes are highlighted nodes, becareful with what alphabet you are transitioning to",
          "answer": "q6",
          "choices": ["q6", "q1, q2, q3","q5, q1" ,"No Transition"]
        },
        "q70": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What is the trnsition from state $\\{q4\\}$ with the alphabet b?",
          "description": "Transition state nodes are highlighted nodes, becareful with what alphabet you are transitioning to to",
          "answer": "No transition",
          "choices": ["q6","q5, q1", "q1, q5, q6","No transition"]
        },
        "q80": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What is the transition from state $\\{q5, q1\\}$ with the alphabet a?",
          "description": "Transition state nodes are highlighted nodes, becareful with what alphabet you are transitioning to to to",
          "answer": "q3",
          "choices": ["q3", "q1, q2, q3","q5, q1" ,"No transition"]
        },
        "q90": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What is the trnsition from state $\\{q5, q1\\}$ with the alphabet b?",
          "description": "Transition state nodes are highlighted nodes, becareful with what alphabet you are transitioning to to to",
          "answer": "No transition",
          "choices": ["q3","q5, q1", "q1, q5, q6","No transition"]
        },
        "q100": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What is the transition from state $\\{q6\\}$ with the alphabet a?",
          "description": "Transition state nodes are highlighted nodes, becareful with what alphabet you are transitioning to to to",
          "answer": "No transition",
          "choices": ["q6", "q1, q2, q3","q5, q1" ,"No transition"]
        },
        "q110": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "question":"What is the transition from state $\\{q6\\}$ with the alphabet b?",
          "description": "Transition state nodes are highlighted nodes, becareful with what alphabet you are transitioning to to to",
          "answer": "No transition",
          "choices": ["q3","q5, q1", "q1, q5, q6","No transition"]
        },
        "q12notUSed": {
          "type": "multiple",
          "src": "../../../AV/FLA/billyu/ui/FAFixer.html",
          "question":"What is the final state?",
          "answer": "q1, q2, q3",
          "choices": ["q0, q1, q2", "q1, q5, q6","q4" ]
        },
        "q130": {
          "type": "select",
          "question":"What are the final state? Note that, any state that include states $q5$ or $q6$ should be a final state",
          "answer": ["q5, q1", "q1, q5, q6", "q6"],
          "choices": ["q0, q1, q2", "q3, q4","q4", "q1, q5, q6", "q3", "q6", "q5, q1"]
        }
      }
    }
  }
  